Lombardi, Tarky; Papers apap261
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers
1966-1967
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lombardi, Tarky
apap261
1.0 cubic ft.
The Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers contain correspondence documenting Lombardi's first term in the New York State Senate from 1966-1967.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Tarky Lombardi initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in the late 1960s. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Tarky Lombardi was born in 1929 and represented the 49th district in Central New York in the New York State Senate as a member of the Republican party. Voters first elected Lombardi to his seat in 1965 and he served until retiring in 1992. Earlier he spent six years on the Syracuse Common Council, including a number of years as its majority leader. A U.S. Army veteran, Lombardi graduated from the New York Military Academy and received a bachelor of science degree as well as a juris doctor from Syracuse University. He and his wife Marianne had five children.
While a State Senator, he served on a number of committees. He was chairman of the Senate Finance Committee from 1989-1992, the Senate Health Committee from 1971-1989, and the Senate Special Committee on the Culture Industry. In addition, Lombardi served as a member of the Codes, Education, Judiciary, Rules, and Veterans committees. During his career, Lombardi was known for his healthcare efforts, as well as advocating for medical malpractice reform. He was chairman of the State Council on Healthcare Financing, and a member of the Assembly on the Legislature, Human Resources and Arts, Tourism, and Cultural Resources committees of the Executive Committee of the National Conference of State Legislatures. Lombardi was a member of the Council of State Governments and chairman of its Committee on Human Resources.
During his career, Lombardi received a number of awards including the Terence Cardinal Cooke Award, Legislator of the Year from the National Association for Homecare, the Arents Medal, and the Simon LeMoyne Medal. He also introduced legislation to establish the New York State Writers Institute at the University at Albany. After retiring from politics, Lombardi returned to work at the Syracuse-based law firm of Devorsetz, Stinziano, Gilberti, Heintz, and Smith P.C. He helped found the firm in 1966, then known as Lombardi Devorsetz Stinziano and Smith, P.C.
Scope and Contents
The Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers document only his earliest years in the New York State Senate (1966-1967). They are almost entirely correspondence with a few newspaper clippings attached to incoming letters. The correspondence is primarily constituent mail and topics vary, but generally relate to a bill pending in the State Senate. There is a small amount of correspondence with fellow legislators. In all instances, the incoming letter is attached to a copy of the outgoing one.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Politics and Politicians; Politicians--New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Syracuse (N.Y.); Clippings; Correspondence; Lombardi, Tarky; New York (State). Legislature. Senate
- Correspondence, 1966 January (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1966 February (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1966 March (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 3-5)
- Correspondence, 1966 April (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 6-7)
- Correspondence, 1966 May (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1966 June (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1966 September (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1966 December (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1967 January (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1967 February (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 13-18)
- Correspondence, 1967 March (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 19-31)
- Correspondence, 1967 April (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 32)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (Tarky Lombardi, Jr. Papers ), Folder 33)